Hello, I'm Phil, and I'm Georgie.
Welcome to Real easy English.
Remember, you can find a vocabulary from this episode and test yourself with a free worksheet on our website,
BBC Learnningenglish dot com.
Hi Georgie, how are you I'm very well Thank you Phil how are you Im really good today We're going to talk about our families and particularly our extended families
Georgie do you have a big family I don't actually I have my two parents a sister and then outside
of that my family's quite small I've got one aunt two uncles and only one.
My uncles has children so I don't have many cousins what about you do you have a big family actually my family's probably similar I've got I've got a brother and
then I've got two aunts.
Three uncles, I've got, well, I've got three cousins that I know and a cousin somewhere lost in Australia.
Oh, wow, interesting.
So we both have quite small extended families Do you see yours much usually only at times like at Christmas,
I'll often see especially my my uncles and my aunts, I see them fairly regularly and my cousins, Yeah,
often Christmas or new year or something like that.
Same with me, really, growing up my uncle, who has children.
Who were my cousins.
They lived quite far away.
So it was similar.
We only really saw them at Christmas and times like that.
And nowadays, I only really see my extended family at.
At events like weddings and sadly funerals, I'd probably like to see them more, but this is life Okay,
Georgie, what about your grandparents Have you been close with your grandparents?
Yeah, so sadly, I don't have any grandparents left, they've all died, but I was really close with particularly my grandmother's.
Both of them lived quite close to me so that was really nice, I could spend a lot of time with them,
they were big personalities, really funny, really loving.
Caring and yeah, I was really close with them What about you Yeah, I think for me it's kind of similar to to your story really,
I don't have any grandparents now.
But when I was younger, the two grandparents that were still alive then I was quite close to, I used to see my granddad every week he used to come and do the shopping for my mum and
I'd see my grandma, Quite regularly as well.
Yeah, I was quite close with them when I was younger to talk about our extended families, we often look at family trees, that's.
Like a diagram that shows your family history, have you researched your family tree,
I personally haven't researched my family tree, but other people in my family.
Have researched it quite a lot, so I can see the bits of my family going back lots of generations,
going back to Scotland, to Ireland, to Norway, to Armenia.
And places like this wow, so your ancestors are from all over the world, it sounds like quite a few places,
yeah, yeah, I I also have not researched my family tree, but I really would like to.
because I do know that my great grandmother was Italian and my great grandfather was from the US,
so I would love to kind of find.
Some family members from those countries and maybe become close with them, I think that would be really interesting to kind of understand more about my history if you want
to know more about your family history, I think you can often look it up, you can you can look it up in records in government offices,
but but also I think there's a lot of websites where you can look things up now and find.
Find out your family history, find out about your ancestors Yes, well, actually, there is a story that my family tells that I'm not sure is true,
but one of my ancestors apparently.
Has a connection to royalty, a big event in history, but again I don't know if it's true,
so I'd love to look it up and find out the facts I think that would be good.
Okay,
let's recap the vocabulary that we've looked at in this episode, starting with close if you're close with.
Or close to a family member, then it's someone who you see a lot and you get on well with your family tree is a diagram or image which shows your family history .
Your ancestors are your relatives from a long time ago lots of people like to look up their ancestors if you look something up,
you try to find out information, for example, by searching online or reading books.
That's it for this episode of real Ey English we'll be back next week with another episode in Ey English.
And if you want to learn to talk more about your family, we have a collection of episodes all about this topic, go tobblearningenglish.com.